Karasuno              Aoba Jousai
Up front!
Slam it down!
打ち下ろせ
前だ
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
しゃぁあ
All right!
Yes! Back-to-back points!
おおしブレイク
よしよし逆転し返した
Yes! Yes! They flipped it back around!
That was amazing!
すごいアタクラインより前に打た
Did it land in front of the attack line?
手首のスナプだけで打てるから威力は弱いけど
Because he hit it by snapping his wrist, the spike wasn't as powerful.
ブロクさえ振れればあの位置は拾えないよな
But as long as it gets past the block,
they can't dig the ball up from that angle.
ていうか影山は意図的に日向に合わせたのか
Push through!
Did Kageyama mean to give that to Hinata?
よしブレイク
Nice spike, Hinata!
日向ナイスキ
Or did he make a mistake?
もしくは影山がミスただけか
Shut up.
うるせぇ
おいすげぇな真下だたぞ
Hey, that was awesome! You basically hit it straight down!
狙たのかよ
Was that intentional?!
Hinata was close to the net, so I made the set close too.
日向がネトに近かたんでトスも近づけました
I'm glad it worked out.
うまくいてよかたです
飛雄の天才ぽいところは
The ingenious part about Tobio
技術とかより多分バカなところだよね
isn't his technique, it's his stupidity.
Where others would probably hold back,
he goes straight for it.
普通なら躊躇うところを迷わず突き進む
おすもう一本獲るぞ
All right! Let's go do it again!
Right!
For better or worse.
それがいい方向でも悪い方向でも
夢中になたら周りが見えず
When he's concentrating, he can't see his surroundings
誰もついて来てないことにも気づかない
and doesn't even realize that
no one's keeping up with him.
But...
Give us another good serve, Tsukishima!
an idiot that goes even further ahead than him has appeared.
飛雄の先を行くバカが現れてしまた
月島もう一本ナイサ
勢いつけ過ぎだつの
You're putting too much strength into that!
ブロクがいないところに跳んだまでのこと
I just jumped up where they weren't any blockers!
ここで来たか１０番
So this is where number ten comes into play.
Yeah.
あああの二人には一々驚かされるよ
Those two never cease to surprise me.
However...
バレは六人で強い方が強い
in volleyball, the team that's better as six wins.
Come on, bring it!
さあ来いやぁ
ここ一本獲るぞ
Let's get this one!
Yeah!
If you understand that, then good.
わかてんならいい
We're going to win!
勝つのは俺達だ
Episode Twenty-four:
The Absolute Limit Switch
Give us a good serve, Tsukishima!
月島ナイサ
Got it!
オライ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
さきの攻撃まぐれはまぐれ
That last attack was just luck.
Left!
レフト
Before it matures...
成長する前に
I'll crush them!
潰す
All right!
よしゃあ
よし同点
All right! We're tied!
Go for it!
一気に行け
All right!
しゃあ
Nice spike, Tanaka!
田中さんナイスキ
龍
Ryuu!
Yeah!
しゃぁあ
Good luck, Matsukawa!
松川先輩ファイトです
We're counting on you!
お願いします
Yeah!
A pinch server, huh?
I'm counting on you here, Yahaba.
ピンチサバか
矢巾一本頼むよ
They're probably strengthening their defense too.
守備強化もあるんじゃないですか
Right!
Give us a good serve, Yahaba!
矢巾ナイサ
With everything I have...
思いきり
旭
Asahi!
Sorry!
すまん
Cover it!
Tanaka!
田中さん
Two blockers!
ブロク２枚
Yahaba!
矢巾
Right!
Kyoutani!
京谷
Crap! It's short!
しまた短い
おおしゃあ
All right!
Did he just hit with his left hand?
今左手で打た
He's right-handed, right?
あいつ右利きだたよな
Did he just do that on the spot?
咄嗟に合わせたのか
He has total control of his body.
自分の体を操るセンスか
Karasuno              Aoba Jousai
That's two points in a row.
ここでブレイクか
If they reach twenty points first, it's going to be rough.
先に２０点台乗せられるときついぞ
Don't let them pull away!
離されんなよ
しゃぁああ
Yeah!
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
しゃぁああ
All right!
You little brat.
クソガキ
Kyoutani...
京谷
We're counting on you!
頼むぞ
Yeah!
しゃあ
Yes! We've caught up.
よしよし追いついた
Yeah, they're really focusing hard.
ああすげぇ集中力だ
田中ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Tanaka!
Those guys never cease to surprise me.
こいつらにはホントに恐れ入るぜ
Got it!
オライ
Watch the right! The right!
ライト来るライト
Number sixteen!
１６番１６番
Stop them!
防げ
Nice contact!
ナイスワンチ
Yes! Keep it going!
よし繋げ繋げ
The receive is off! Watch the left side!
乱れてるレフト注意
Get back!
下れ
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
Wow...
すげぇ
もかいもかい
One more!
Someone cover it!
Left!
レフト
Damn it!
All right!
よしゃぁああ
Now we're in the 20s!
これで２０点台
Karasuno            Aoba Jousai
They got to twenty first.
先に獲られたか
慌てなくていい
We don't have to panic.
まだ１点だ
It's still just a one point lead.
All right!
よしゃあ
頼むぞ
We're counting on you!
It's him again!
出てきた
The pinch server who got five points in a row during the second set!
２セト目に５点連続で獲たあのピンサだ
We're counting on you, Yamaguchi!
頼むぜ山口
Stay calm!
落ち着いてな
Give it your all!
思いきり行けよ
Right!
Go!
Tadashi!
行けぇ
忠ィ
Give us a good serve!
Yamaguchi!
ナイサ
山口くんさきの頼むよ
Do that thing again!
Yamaguchi.
山口
Go hit a good serve.
ナイサ一本
Yeah.
Karasuno              Aoba Jousai
You can do this!
ナイサ
It's going out.
アウト
No...
This time it went long?!
今度は伸びんのかよ
Yay!
Yeah!
What?!
Whoa! He actually kept it in play!
繋ぎやがた
The last hit's all yours, Watari!
渡ラスト
Right.
Here's our chance!
チャンスボル
A synchronized attack!
シンクロ攻撃
Yeah!
だしゃぁああ
Damn, his switch is totally flipped on.
Nice receive, Iwa.
ナイスレシブ岩ちゃん
完全にスイチ入てる
Nice one, Iwaizumi!
岩泉さんナイス
Wow...
すげぇ
Makki!
フェイント
A tip!
くそが
Damn it!
Yes! We managed to limit number twelve to one serve!
よし１２番のサブ一本で切た
All right!
Nice tip!
ナイスキ
Yeah!
小ちゃい頃はスパイクだけが楽しくてそればかやてたけど
When I was a kid, all I did was spike because it was fun, but now I can truly say this.
今になて心底思う
相手の完璧な一発を拾うレシブの快感を知てよかた
I'm glad I learned how good it feels to dig out the perfect spike.
Shake it off, Yamaguchi!
山口ドンマイ
Is that seriously the same guy from the interhigh prelims?
それにしても
Give us a good one, Hanamaki!
花巻ナイサ
アレは本当にインタハイ予選の時の奴と同一人物かよ
You didn't do anything wrong.
今のはしょうがねぇ相手がすごかた
The other team was just too good.
しゃああ
Shake it off.
ドンマイです
Nice receive, Tanaka!
ナイスレシブ田中さん
Yes, sir.
Yamaguchi!
山口
That was a great serve.
いいサブだたぞ
Each and every point carries so much weight.
一本一本が重いですね
Yeah.
They're just gonna have to stay on top of the ball and keep stacking up points one at a time.
ひたすらボルに喰らいついて
１点ずつ積み上げていくしか
That's the only way they can win.
それしか道はねぇ
All right!
Karasuno                  Aoba Jousai
よしゃあ
Neither side is backing down.
どちも譲らないな
If this turns into a deuce again,
will they keep going until they get a two-point—
これまたデュスまでなたら２点差つくまでやるの
No.
They're not gonna have time to think about that.
そんな悠長なこと言てらんないぞ
Bring it!
さぁ来い
Seriously?
マジかよ
All right!
よしゃぁああ
Nice serve!
ナイサ
What was that?
何なんだよ
He can hit such an amazing serve in this tense situation?
この場面であんなサブ
Is he some kind of monster?
バケモンかよあいつ
One more!
もう一本
All right!
Karasuno                 Aoba Jousai
よしゃあ
青城マチポイントだ
Seijou's at match point.
まあアレだ
It's that again.
We're just gonna have to dig it out.
拾うしかないすね
Yeah!
切り替え切り替え
Switch gears!
Their mental strength is amazing.
すごい精神力だ
Right!
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
They must be under an immense amount of pressure right now.
相当なプレシャがあるはずなのに
If we can get a hand on it, we'll make it work somehow!
触りゃあなんとかなる
We're not gonna lose!
負けねぇよ俺達は
Yeah!
Give it your all!
思いきり行けよ
But of course.
当然
さあいよいよだぞ
Well, it's time.
You have to dig out his serve, no matter what!
絶対拾えよ
Olé!
Yes!
しゃぁああ
All right!
よしゃ
及川のサブ切た
They stopped Oikawa!
It's still match point for Seijou, though.
でもまだ青城のマチポイント
Karasuno                  Aoba Jousai
The wall in front of this next point is high.
この１点の壁は高い
Whoa. It's all over for Karasuno if they don't score here,
烏野１点でもミスればおしまいなのに
yet they're switching out their libero?
ここでリベロ不在か
Sir.
先生
Right.
Yeah!
しゃあ
This is the final showdown.
最後の勝負だ
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
Yeah!
しゃあ
This is the final showdown.
最後の勝負だ
Oh, they're gonna do the tactical single point by two setters!
ここで戦術的ワンポイントツセタか
Yeah!
If they can't score two in a row, they're done.
ここでブレイクできなきゃ終わり
Yeah!
Please!
頼むぞ
Yeah!
２セト目ん時みたくうまくはまてくれ
Do what you did back in the second set!
Yeah!
スガさんナイサ頼んます
Give us a good serve, Suga!
Yeah!
こいつの終盤で見せる集中力はどから来てんだ
How is he always able to concentrate so intensely at the end of a match?
Not that he has anything else going for him!
集中力だけだけどな
Huh? Why are you picking a fight with Hinata?
お前なんで日向に喧嘩売てんの
Let's finish it right here!
これで決めるよ
Yeah!
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
一本集中
Focus on one point at a time!
このサブミスたら終わり
If I mess up this serve, it's all over.
ナイサ一本
Give us a good serve!
行け
Go!
And if we can't survive our opponent's attack, it's over.
相手の攻撃を凌げなくても終わり
Here I go!
行くぞ
Is it in or out?
インかアウトか
Is it going to be me or Iwaizumi?
俺か岩泉さんか
Damn, they got it!
クソ拾た
But the ace is out of the picture now!
けどエスを牽制
Center!
センタ
しゃあ
Yeah!
止めた
You stopped it!
Hinata!
Shouyou!
日向
翔陽
そりゃミドルブロカなんだから
I mean, he is a middle blocker.
He's supposed to be able to block.
ブロクできなきゃだめでしょ
すまんと思てる
I feel bad, really!
Great job taking that hit, Kageyama!
影山もよく堪えたな
Karasuno                  Aoba Jousai
烏野追いついた
Karasuno tied it up!
It's a deuce!
デュス
サセン
Sorry.
ドンマイ
Shake it off!
次次
Focus on the next one!
Rather than trying to block it,
it was more like he jumped for the ball at all costs.
止めに行たというより
とにかくボルに飛びついたという感じか
毎度チビちゃんの反応の速さには舌を巻くね
I'm always astonished by Shorty's quick reaction time.
Do it again, Suga!
スガさんもう一本
行くぞ
Here I go.
前前
Up front!
ニャロ
Damn it!
Whoa, that was close! It barely went over!
危ねぇ前ギリギリ
It broke their defenses!
崩した
Now he's trying to get Iwaizumi off balance?
今度は岩泉の揺さぶりか
He may be Mr. Pleasant,
but his serves aren't pleasant at all!
爽やかくんのくせにサブは全然爽やかじゃねぇな
センタ
Center!
前前前
In the front!
Hit the ground!
落ちろ
俺が取る
I got it!
Yes!
Mr. Pleasant hit it first.
ファストタチは爽やかくん
これでさきの攻撃パタンはない
Now they can't do that attack from before!
Go!
行け
Even if you can't block it, at least make some contact!
止められなくても触れ
Give it to me!
持て来い
You goddamn brats!
クソガキ共
Ka—
影山
Kageyama!
やたな
知てる
I know.
ナイス影山
Nice, Kageyama!
Well done!
よくやたな
お前すごいぞ
けど俺は
But...
I won't lose.
負けない
Karasuno              Aoba Jousai
Just one more point!
これで後１点
That was awesome, Tobio!
飛雄かけぇぞ
Man, when Sugawara touched the ball first,
I thought that meant Kageyama wouldn't be attacking.
いやあ俺も菅原がファストタチイコル
影山の攻撃はないて思ちゃたもんな
Yeah, but everyone's got the impression that when Sugawara's in the game, he's up to something,
ああ後は菅原が入てくると何かやらかすて印象があるから
so their attention is drawn to him a little.
ほんの少しでもそちに意識が行ちゃうんだよな
Damn, that really pisses me off!
クソ腹立つ
That's definitely Oikawa's junior.
さすが及川の後輩だな
He's got a setter's disposition,
staying confident when it's all on the line.
あの土壇場での強気もセタの資質てやつだな
Yeah, he does.
まあ確かに
分けて欲しいわ
I'd love some of that confidence, to be honest.
自分の力の上限をもう悟たていうのか
Have you found the limits of your abilities?
Even though your technique, body, and mind haven't been perfected?
技も体も精神も何一つ出来上がてないのに
自分より優れた何かを持てる人間は
People who are naturally better than you have been different from you since the day they were born.
生まれた時点で自分とは違ている
それを覆すことなど
No matter how hard you work, how well you strategize, or who your teammates are, you can't change that.
どんな努力工夫仲間をもてしても不可能だ
そう嘆くのは
You can complain after you've actually done everything you possibly can.
全ての正しい努力を尽くしてからで遅くない
自分は天才とは違うからと嘆き諦めることより
Rather than despairing and giving up because you're not a genius,
believe that this isn't the limit of your strength
and continue on the path straight ahead of you.
自分の力はこんなものではないと信じて
ひたすらますぐに道を進んでいくことは
It may be a harsh road, but...
辛く苦しい道であるかもしれないけれど
Today might be the day you seize
the chance to let your talent bloom.
才能の開花のチャンスを掴むのは今日かもしれない
もしくは明日か明後日か来年か
It could be tomorrow, the day after, next year.
３０歳になてからかも
Maybe even when you're thirty.
I'm not sure if physique has anything to do with it,
体格ばかりは何ともいえないけど
ないと思てたらたぶん一生ないんだ
but if you think it'll never come, it probably never will.
やぱ及川さん最近なんか変わたよな
Oikawa's seems different lately, doesn't he?
Push it, push it, push it, push it, push it, Seijou!
Rule the Court
行け行け行け行け行け行け青城
Go, go, go, go, go, go, Seijou!
Go, go, Karasuno!
Push it, push it, Karasuno!
行け行け行け烏野
押せ押せ押せ烏野
決めろ
Hey, say it together!
おい合わせろよ
If they hit a serve way up in the front again, I'll get it.
さきのくらい前に落とされたら俺が取る
後ろは任せた
I'm leaving the rest to you.
Right!
Don't let your guard down.
油断すんなよまたこちに落としてくる可能性もある
They might try to drop it on us again.
Keep your eye on the ball.
目の前の一点な
Right!
Make sure to aim for the edges!
際際狙てけよ
I know.
分かてるよ中途半端やたら即行叩かれるから
If I half-ass it, they'll instantly fire back at us.
All we need to do is get a hand on it when blocking!
ブロクとにかく触るぞ
Yeah!
Let's get this point back!
取り返す
Let's score here!
ここ獲るぞ
Yeah!
Karasuno              Aoba Jousai
スガさんナイサ
Give us a good serve, Suga!
Up front!
前だ岩泉さん
Iwaizumi!
All right! He's off balance!
よし牽制した
Damn it!
Ryuu!
龍
行けぇ
Go!
ここで決めろ
Let's finish this!
Damn, he dug it out!
Hanamaki!
花巻さん
拾いやがた
But...
乱れた
it's way off course!
頼む及川
It's all up to you, Oikawa!
チャンスボル
Here's our chance!
コト外から
A super-long and fast setup from outside the court...
タイミングの早い超ロングセトアプ
４番が入てきてる
Number four's going for it!
Talent is something you make bloom!
才能は開花させるもの
センスは磨くもの
Instinct is something you polish!
ドンピシャ
It's perfect!
Damn it!
しゃあ
Yeah!
ラスト
Get the last hit!
６人で強いほうが強い
The team who's better as six wins!
Keep the rally going!
繋げ
This is our chance!
チャンスボル
チャンスにさせて
Like hell...
そから打つ気か
He's gonna hit it from there?!
...you'll get that chance!
たまるか
京谷ナイス
Nice, Kyoutani!
Hit it, Kageyama!
叩け影山
クソみともねぇ
Shit. Talk about lame!
Give it to me!
寄越せぇ
来い
Come.
お前の最強の武器で来い
Come at me with your ultimate weapon,
飛雄
Tobio!
セトアプのモション読まれた
They saw it coming!
All...
よしゃあ
...right!
Karasuno                Aoba Jousai
We won! We won!
勝た勝たぞ
嶋田お前もしかして泣いてるのか
Shimada... are you crying?
いいやちょとコンタクトがずれただけだ
N-No, my contact lens just slipped...
But you're wearing glasses.
お前メガネじゃん
Episode Twenty-five:
Declaration of War
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュ宣戦布告
"Declaration of War."